RG 089, Department of Transportation
Connecticut State Library
- Series 25. Commissioner, 1941-2003, bulk 1973-2003; 88 cubic feet
  - 2007-038
    - Interdepartment correspondence, 1998-2003 (Box 7)
      - State Properties Review Board (Box 9)
      - State Treasurer, Office of (Box 9)
      - State Insurance & Risk Management Board *SIRMB) (Box 9)
      - University of Connecticut (Box 9)
      - Veterans' Affairs, Department of (Box 9)
      - Working Group on State Preparation & Security (Box 9)
      - Comptroller (Box 9)
        Out of sequence.
    - Dept. of Transportation Bureau correspondence, 1998-2003
      - Affirmative Action (Box 10)
      - Aviation & Ports (Box 10)
        - State Pier (Box 10)
        - Ports (Box 10)
      - Finance & Administration (Box 10)
      - Commissioner's memoranda (Box 10)
      - Communication, Director of (Box 10)
      - Engineering & Highway Operations, 1999-2003 (Box 10)
      - State Traffic Commission (Box 10)
      - Management Services (Box 10)
      - Policy & Planning (Box 10)
      - Public Transportation (Box 11)
      - Bradley International Airport (Box 11)
      - Bradley Expansion Program (Box 11)
      - Bradley International Airport Hotel (Box 11)
      - Bradley International Commission (Box 11)
      - Danbury Airport (Box 11)
      - Groton/New London Airport (Box 11)
      - Sikorsky Airport (Box 11)
      - Airport - general (Box 11)
      - Aircraft registration (Box 11)
      - Brainard Field, Hartford (Box 11)
      - Waterbury-Oxford Airport (Box 11)
      - Railroads (Box 11)
        - Amtrak (Box 11)
        - Metro-North (Box 11)
        - Shore Line East (Box 11)
        - Providence & Worcester Railroad (Box 11)
    - United States Government Correspondence, 1998-2003 (Box 11)
      - Congress, 1999-2003 (Box 11)
      - U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (Box 11)
      - Federal Highway Administration (Box 12)
      - FHWA - Scanning Program Documents, 1990-2003 (Box 12)
      - Federal Railway Administration (Box 12)
      - Federal Transit Administration (Box 12)
      - U.S. Department of Transportation (Box 12)
      - U.S. Department of Transportation - Transportation security (Box 12)
      - Administration - Transportation Security Administration (Box 12)
    - Correspondence to Associations and Committees, 1998-2003 (Box 12)
      - American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials (AASHTO) (Box 12)
      - American Road Builders Association (Box 12)
      - Central Connecticut Transportation Association (Box 12)
      - Conference of New England Governors (Box 12)
      - Connecticut Association of Street and Highway Officials (Box 12)
      - Connecticut Bituminous Concrete Producers Association (Box 12)
      - Connecticut Business & Industry Association (Box 12)
      - Connecticut Construction Industries (Box 12)
      - Metropool (Box 12)
      - Motor Transport - MTAC (Box 12)
      - National Highway Safety Administration (Box 12)
      - National Transportation Safety Board (Box 12)
      - New England Governor's Conference (Box 12)
      - New England Regional Transportation (Box 12)
      - New England Transportation Consortium (Box 12)
      - Northeastern Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials (NASHTO) (Box 12)
      - Regional Planning agencies (Box 12)
        - Capitol Region Council of Governments (Box 12)
        - Greater Bridgeport (Box 12)
        - Northeast Connecticut (Box 12)
        - South Central Regional Council of Southwestern Region Government (Box 12)
        - Metro Planning Organization (Box 12)
        - Valley (Box 12)
        - Southwestern Area Commerce & Industry Association of Connecticut (Box 12)
        - Greater Bridgeport Transport (Box 12)
      - Transportation Strategy Board (Box 12)
    - Subject Files, 1998-2003
      - Adriaen's Landing (Box 13)
      - Automated fuel system benefit - overview (Box 13)
      - Bradley Board of Directors membership lsit 2002-2003 (Box 13)
      - Bradley International Airport - Executive Council, 2003 (Box 13)
      - Bradley International Airport - Executive Council minutes (Box 13)
      - Bradley International Airport - Executive Council report (Box 13)
      - Bridges (Box 13)
        - Baldwin Bridge (Box 13)
        - Quinnipiac River Bridge (Box 13)
      - Connecticut Statewide Bicycle & Pedestrian Transportation Plan, 1999 March (Box 13)
      - Budget (Box 14)
      - Care & Share (Box 14)
      - Connecticut employees campaign (Box 14)
      - Connecticut climate change (Box 14)
      - Connecticut climate change - action plan (Box 14)
      - Code of fair practices (Box 14)
      - L.K. Comstock & Company, Inc. (Box 14)
      - Construction Contract - bidding & award manual (Box 14)
      - Context sensitive design (Box 14)
      - Consultants, miscellaneous (Box 14)
      - Contract compliance (Box 14)
      - Consultant selection (Box 14)
      - Connecticut Regional Institute fo 21st Century (Box 14)
      - Connecticut Transit (Box 14)
      - Consultants engineers approval (Box 14)
      - Consultant prequalification (Box 14)
      - Disadvantaged Business Enterprise/Women Business Enterprise (DBE/WBE) (Box 14)
      - Dept. of Transportation Employee Recognition Program (Box 14)
      - Delegation of authority (Box 14)
      - Department of Transportation headquarters building - Newington (Box 14)
      - Emergency declaration (Box 14)
      - Emergency shutdown (Box 14)
      - Enhancement projects (Box 14)
      - Environmental streamlining - President's executive order (Box 14)
      - Equipment (Box 14)
      - Federal aid (Box 14)
      - Freedom of Information, 2001-2003 (Box 14)
      - Incident management (Box 15)
      - Intermodal Surface Transport Efficiency Act of 1991 (Box 15)
      - IPPS manual (Box 15)
      - Leases (Box 15)
      - Marine pilot rotation (Box 15)
      - Master transportation plan (Box 15)
      - Merritt Parkway (Box 15)
      - Metric conversion (Box 15)
      - Middlesex Corporation (Box 15)
      - PARS rating (Box 15)
      - Privatization (Box 15)
      - Rideshare (Box 15)
      - Route 11 (Box 15)
      - Route 72 (Box 15)
      - Standardization Committee (Box 16)
      - Scenic road submission (Box 16)
      - State Emergency Response Commission (SERC) (Box 16)
      - Signs (Box 16)
      - Smart Route (Box 16)
      - Small Business Enterprises (SBE) (Box 16)
      - Southeast Corridor study (Box 16)
      - Southwest Corridor report (Box 16)
      - 1995 Special Olympics World Games (Box 16)
      - Speed limits (Box 16)
      - Stadiums (Box 16)
      - State highway system (Box 16)
      - Special tax obligation bonds (Box 16)
      - Thomas Commission recommendations (Box 16)
      - Traffic reduction tax credit certification (Box 16)
      - Transportation Appropriation Act of 2000 (Box 16)
      - Transportation Strategy Board (Box 16)
      - Transportation Summit 2000 (Box 17)
      - Travel authorizations (Box 17)
      - Truck stop & rest areas (Box 17)
      - Truck weight safety (Box 17)
      - United Way appeal (Box 17)
      - Unmetered utility billings (Box 17)
      - Connecticut Employees Union Independent vs. Connecticut Dept. of Transportation (Box 17)
      - Connecticut Employees Union Independent (Box 17)
      - Work zone safety (Box 17)
      - Y2K assignment (Box 17)
      - Homeland security (Box 17)
    - Governor's correspondence log, 1999-2003 (Box 18)
  - 2007-041
    Commissioners G. Albert Hill, Edward Ives, A. Earl Wood, J. William Burns, James Sullivan, James Byrnes.
    - Commissioner's administrative memorandum, 1941-1991 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence from Governor's Office
      - 1992-1995 (Box 2)
      - 1996-1999 (Box 3)
    - Record of legal instruments, 1978-2003 (Box 4)
    - Freedom of Information (FOI) request - Sent to Governor's Office Legal Office, 1999-2002 (Box 4)
- Series 33. Photographs, 1988-1989; .5 cubic feet
  - Housatonic Railroad Company, 1988-1989; 1 album; 1994-031
    Includes note dated 1989 December: "This album shows some of the rehabilitation work performed on the Berkshire Line, most of which had been out of service/abandoned for 17 years until reopening in April 1989. The Housatonic Railroad has performed all rehabilitation work with its own employees and equipment under a joint FRA / Connecticut DOT / Housatonic project. One each page the top photo was taken in September 1988 and the bottom picture in November 1989 at the following locations: 1 - Boardman's Bridge, New Milford; 2 - Gaylordsville; 3 - South Kent Road, South Kent; 4 - Bulls Bridge Road, South Kent; 5 - Camp Getaway, Kent; 6 - Route 7, Kent; 7 - Just north of Route 7 Crossing, Kent; 8 - Kent Falls; 9 - Just north of Kent Falls; 10 - Cornwall Bridge (No Sept. 1988 photo); 11 - Route 128, West Cornwall (No Sept. 1988 photo); 12 - Route 126 & Sand Road Crossings, Falls Village."
- Series 34. Bureau of Aeronautics. Bradley International Airport. Automatically Controlled Transportation (ACT), 1974-1975; 2.75 cubic feet; 1997-013
  The ACT is also known as the People Mover.
  - Ford sales brochures, specifications (Box 1)
  - Proposals (Box 1)
  - Specifications (Box 1)
  - Specifications, general contract, Smith, Hinchman & Grylls Associates, Inc., 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Ford reports, 2 folders (Box 1-2)
  - Vehicle service logs, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Radio communications system - service manual (Box 2)
  - Components - operating manuals, specifications, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Purchase notice revisions - Walbridge, Aldinger Company, 2 folders (Box 2-3)
  - Purchase order revisions - Subcontractors, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Concrete guideway by Concrete Technology Corp. - inspection reports (Box 3)
  - Haller Labs, Inc. - concrete testing, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Walbridge, Aldinger Company - daily reports, 2 folders (Box 3-4)
  - Vehicle Bradley I, computer printout (Box 4)
  - Vehicle Bradley II, computer printout (Box 4)
  - Register of visitors - Bradley site (Box 4)
  - Blueprints (Box 4-6)
- Series 35. Mianus River Bridge Collapse Investigation, 1983; .5 cubic feet; 2001-006
  - Exhibits, 1954-1983 (Box 1)
    Contents: Exhibit I, Hearing authority; II, Weather Data;. Not present: III, Witness list; VIII, Findings.
    Exhibit V includes 25 photographic prints.
  - National Transportation Safety Board, Highway Accident Report, Collapse of a section of Interstate Route 95 Highway Bridge over the Manus River, Greenwich, Connecticut, June 28 1983 (Box 1)
    Adopted July 19, 1984.
- Series 36. Legislative Proposals, 1994; 1999-094; 1 folder
  Includes the following: 94-01, 94-02, 94-03, 94-04, 94-05, 94-06, 94-08, 94-10, 94-12, 94-13, 94-14, 94-15, 94-16, 94-17, 94-19, 94-22.
- Series 38. Films, 1973-1996; 124 cubic feet
  - Road Logs, 1973-1996; 885 reels of 35mm film (124 cubic feet); 2013-003
    To view digitized copies of these films, contact Bradley J. Overturf, Transportation Photolog Supervisor, Bureau of Policy and Planning, Connecticut Dept. of Transportation, at 860-594-2160 (Newington) or 860-258-0319 (Rocky Hill).
    Also see the website.
  - "Liquid Roadway Deicing", 1978 June 23; 1 reel of 16mm film; 2013-007